[
  {
    "question": "The “Spanish flu” originated in",
    "a": "Spain",
    "b": "the United States",
    "c": "Germany",
    "d": "France",
    "e": "the Philippines",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many Americans were killed by influenza in comparison to American deaths in World War I?",
    "a": "twice as many",
    "b": "half as many",
    "c": "seven times as many",
    "d": "fourteen times as many",
    "e": "nine times as many",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following people accompanied President Woodrow Wilson on his trip to the Paris Peace Conference?",
    "a": "the Speaker of the House",
    "b": "the Senate majority leader",
    "c": "the Senate president pro tempore",
    "d": "the First Lady",
    "e": "the Vice President",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which economist declared President Woodrow Wilson to be a powerful “philosopher”?",
    "a": "Joseph Schumpter",
    "b": "Alfred Marshall",
    "c": "John Hicks",
    "d": "John Maynard Keynes",
    "e": "Alvin Hansen",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "One of Woodrow Wilson’s campaign slogans in the 1916 presidential election was",
    "a": "Facing the Future",
    "b": "To Assure Continued Prosperity",
    "c": "He Kept Us Out Of War",
    "d": "Win with Wilson",
    "e": "Let the People Rule",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which nation owned the ocean liner Lusitania?",
    "a": "the United States",
    "b": "Britain",
    "c": "Denmark",
    "d": "France",
    "e": "Italy",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "A popular nickname for American soldiers during World War I was",
    "a": "doughboys",
    "b": "mustangs",
    "c": "grunts",
    "d": "bowlheads",
    "e": "yankees",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who commanded the American Expeditionary Force during World War I?",
    "a": "John Pershing",
    "b": "Edwin Babbit",
    "c": "William Graves",
    "d": "Harold Fiske",
    "e": "Alex Cole",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Woodrow Wilson MOST directly supported the philosophy of",
    "a": "protectionism",
    "b": "internationalism",
    "c": "isolationism",
    "d": "militarism",
    "e": "commercialism",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which clause was NOT part of Woodrow Wilson’s Fourteen Points?",
    "a": "self-determinism",
    "b": "military limitations",
    "c": "transparent negotiations",
    "d": "free sea travel",
    "e": "free trade",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why were Woodrow Wilson’s ideas popular among non-Europeans?",
    "a": "He declared the United States would protect them.",
    "b": "He delivered radio speeches in their native languages.",
    "c": "He welcomed immigration to the United States.",
    "d": "He supported an international alliance.",
    "e": "He advocated ending colonial rule.",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "The French and British diplomats at the Paris Peace Conference PRIMARILY saw Woodrow Wilson as a(n)",
    "a": "savior",
    "b": "despot",
    "c": "idealist",
    "d": "militarist",
    "e": "pacifist",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "What was Germany NOT compelled to do under the Treaty of Versailles?",
    "a": "divide into multiple occupied zones",
    "b": "decrease its military strength",
    "c": "forfeit its colonies",
    "d": "pay large war reparation sums",
    "e": "cede territory to France",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "What disorder affected Woodrow Wilson’s speech after his return from the Paris Peace Conference?",
    "a": "dysarthria",
    "b": "dysphagia",
    "c": "apraxia",
    "d": "aphasia",
    "e": "cephalalgia",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which country had NOT ratified the Treaty of Versailles by July 1919?",
    "a": "Britain",
    "b": "Italy",
    "c": "France",
    "d": "the United States",
    "e": "Germany",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
    {
    "question": "What portion of the Senate needed to approve the Treaty of Versailles to ratify it?",
    "a": "three-fourths",
    "b": "three-fifths",
    "c": "one-fourth",
    "d": "one-half",
    "e": "two-thirds",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
   {
    "question": "Henry Cabot Lodge was the chairman of the",
    "a": "Diplomatic Affairs Committee",
    "b": "Foreign Relations Committee",
    "c": "Global Strategy Committee",
    "d": "Senate Intelligence Committee",
    "e": "Judiciary Committee",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which United States president was Lodge’s close friend?",
    "a": "William Howard Taft",
    "b": "Woodrow Wilson",
    "c": "Calvin Coolidge",
    "d": "Theodore Roosevelt",
    "e": "William McKinley",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "The term “Reservationists” describes senators who",
    "a": "opposed all forms of international cooperation",
    "b": "supported the original version of the League of Nations",
    "c": "helped draft the Fourteen Points",
    "d": "proposed several amendments to the League of Nations Charter",
    "e": "rejected the Treaty of Versailles under all conditions",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
   {
    "question": "Which article of the League of Nations’ Charter did Lodge criticize MOST?",
    "a": "Article XXI",
    "b": "Article IX",
    "c": "Article X",
    "d": "Article V",
    "e": "Article II",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
   {
    "question": "Which of the following senators was an “Irreconcilable?”",
    "a": "James M. Cox",
    "b": "Albert B. Fall",
    "c": "Charles Evan Hughes",
    "d": "Henry Cabot Lodge",
    "e": "William E. Borah",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
   {
    "question": "How many amendments to the Treaty of Versailles did HLodge propose?",
    "a": "forty-two",
    "b": "fifty-four",
    "c": "fifty-nine",
    "d": "fifty-one",
    "e": "sixty",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
   {
    "question": "Wilson submitted the final version of the Treaty of Versailles in",
    "a": "1916",
    "b": "1915",
    "c": "1919",
    "d": "1912",
    "e": "1910",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
   {
    "question": "How did Wilson respond to opposition from Republican leaders?",
    "a": "He invited opposing leaders to co-write a new treaty.",
    "b": "He accepted their amendments and revised the treaty.",
    "c": "He requested the Supreme Court to settle the dispute.",
    "d": "He suspended Senate proceedings in protest.",
    "e": "He set out to plead his case directly to the American population.",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
   {
    "question": "What was the name of Wilson’s private railcar?",
    "a": "The Providence",
    "b": "The Liberty Belle",
    "c": "Plymouth",
    "d": "The Mayflower",
    "e": "Columbia",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
   {
    "question": "Wilson’s final public speech took place in",
    "a": "Pueblo, Colorado",
    "b": "Cheyenne, Wyoming",
    "c": "Kansas City, Missouri",
    "d": "Albuquerque, New Mexico",
    "e": "Columbus, Ohio",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
   {
    "question": "What disorder affected Woodrow Wilson’s speech after his return from the Paris Peace Conference?",
    "a": "dysarthria",
    "b": "dysphagia",
    "c": "apraxia",
    "d": "aphasia",
    "e": "cephalalgia",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
   {
    "question": "Which country had NOT ratified the Treaty of Versailles by July 1919?",
    "a": "Britain",
    "b": "Italy",
    "c": "France",
    "d": "the United States",
    "e": "Germany",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },

   {
    "question": "What disorder affected Woodrow Wilson’s speech after his return from the Paris Peace Conference?",
    "a": "dysarthria",
    "b": "dysphagia",
    "c": "apraxia",
    "d": "aphasia",
    "e": "cephalalgia",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
   {
    "question": "Which country had NOT ratified the Treaty of Versailles by July 1919?",
    "a": "Britain",
    "b": "Italy",
    "c": "France",
    "d": "the United States",
    "e": "Germany",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },

   {
    "question": "What disorder affected Woodrow Wilson’s speech after his return from the Paris Peace Conference?",
    "a": "dysarthria",
    "b": "dysphagia",
    "c": "apraxia",
    "d": "aphasia",
    "e": "cephalalgia",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },

   {
    "question": "Which country had NOT ratified the Treaty of Versailles by July 1919?",
    "a": "Britain",
    "b": "Italy",
    "c": "France",
    "d": "the United States",
    "e": "Germany",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  }



]
